Guide to the Harry J. Rathbun Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Harry J. Rathbun papers
1955-1996
SC0969
Rathbun, Harry J. (Harry John), 1894-
0.5 Linear feet
One audio reel from a lecture in The Sequoia Seminar series on "Realizing Our Highest Potentialities" given at the Palo Alto Library, 1955.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Alternative Formats
Digital file available for patron use; please consult with the University Archivist for access.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Harry J. Rathbun first studied engineering at Stanford University, earning his A.B. in 1916 and his Engineer's degree in 1920. After several years as an engineer, he returned to Stanford to study law, receiving his J.D. in 1929. He joined the faculty in the Law School that same year, reaching the rank of professor in 1937; his specialty was business law. Rathbun, along with his wife Emilia, founded several non-profit organizations interested in social justice and anti-war issues.
Description of the Collection
Collection contains one audio reel from a lecture in The Sequoia Seminar series on "Realizing Our Highest Potentialities" given at the Palo Alto Library, 1955.
Access Terms
Rathbun, Harry J. (Harry John), 1894-; Stanford University. School of Law--Faculty.; Stanford University. School of Law. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Audiotapes.; Lectures.; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Lecture, 1955; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2010-022
- Audiovisual recordings, Accession ARCH-2011-193
  - Henry and Emilia Rathbun - Walking to Alas, Waterfall Interior, Woodland Cabins, 1983 Jul 8; 1.1; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 1)
  - Henry & Emilia Rathbun at Sequoia Seminar, 1983 Jul 7-8; 1.2; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam-SP) (Box 1)
  - Harry J. Rathbun at Stanford: Walking, standing, etc. on campus, 1982 Oct 22; 1.3; 1.0 (Box 1)
  - Interview with Harry R. @ Ben Lomond, 1.4; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam-SP) (Box 1)
  - Emilia on History, 1.5; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam-SP) (Box 1)
  - H.J.R. Dinner Speech at Bechtel Exectutive's Seminar, 1957 Feb 14; 2.1; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Harry Rathbun - San Francisco, 1957 Sep 22; 2.2; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - "A Vision for Our Time", 1966 May 15; 2.3; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Leon & Lucille Carley, 2.4; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Helen R[?], Song "Barter" by Sara Teasdale, 2.5; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Don & Virgina Fitton, 1961 Sep 20; 2.6; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Paula Sheller, 1961 Sep 22; 2.7; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Jim & MaryLou Shoolery, 1961 Sep 20; 2.8; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Ann Burton, 1961 Sep 21; 2.9; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Lou Riley, narration Harry Rathbun, 1961 Sep 20; 2.10; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Gene Franklin, 1961 Sep 29; 2.11; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - George Brunn, Francis Geddes, directly afterward - Ann Burton & Bill Burton separately, 1961 Sep 22; 2.12; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Louis & Jean Sloss, 1961 Sep 20; 2.13; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Rabbi Joseph Glasser, 1961 Sep 21; 2.14; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - John Levy, 1961 Sep 19; 2.15; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - George Brunn, Francis Geddes, 1961 Sep 22; 2.16; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar - Jim Burch, Palo Alto Family Seminar, 1961 Sep 18; 2.17; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - 2nd Leadership Seminar - 11:30am Chapt IX Sec. 50, 1956 Nov 3; 2.18; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - 2nd Leadership Seminar - 10:15am Sat Chapt IX Sect 42-49, 1956 Nov 3; 2.19; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - 2nd Leadership Seminar (Emelia)- 9:30am - 10:30am Sat, 1956 Nov 3; 2.20; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - 2nd Leadership Seminar (Emelia)- 12:00pm-1:00pm, 1956 Nov 3; 2.21; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - 2nd Leadership Seminar (Emelia)- 10:30am-12:00pm, 1956 Nov 3; 2.22; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Speech delivered by Dr. Harry Rathbun Professor Emeritus of Law, Stanford University at Dept. of Army Personnel Management..., 1961 May 10; 2.23; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Some Implications for Nuclear Age Man (1 of 2), 1960 Dec 29; 2.24; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Some Implications for Nuclear Age Man (2 of 2), 1960 Dec 29; 2.25; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar KPFK/KPFA Documentary, 1962 Jan; 2.26; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar Documentary by Art Wadsworth KPFK-FM, Los Angeles (1of 2), 1961 Dec 26; 2.27; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Sequoia Seminar Documentary by Art Wadsworth KPFK-FM, Los Angeles (2of 2), 1961 Dec 26; 2.28; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Harry & Emilia Rathbun on Sequoia Seminar, 2.29; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Psychocybernetics - Luring, 2.30; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Psychocybernetics - Luring, 2.31; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Psychocybernetics - Luring, 2.32; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - New Sphere Tape No. 1 - Introduction, 2.33; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - HJR's/RBR, 2.34; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - New Sphere Discussion Tape: Psycho-Cybernetics, Bill Luring, Parts 1, 2, 3, 2.35; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Psycho-Cybernetics, Intro, 2.36; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - "Eyewitness News" KPIX Stanford, 1968 May 26; 2.37; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Unlabeled, 2.38; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - Harry Rathbun Interview Sequoia Seminar Ben Lomond, CA, 1983; 83-3006; 1 videotape(s) (Betacam-SP) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Meeting Henry Burton Sharman & Sharman's Personality, 1983 Jul 8; 83-3008; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - 1934 Sierra Seminar, Early Years at Stanford & Emilia Rathbun's Background, 1983 Jul 8; 83-3009; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - First Seminar at Camp Minnesing & Henry Burton Sharman's Methods & Background, 1983 Jul 8; 83-3010; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Henry Burton Sharman's Thesis, China & Yen Jing University, Sharman's Personal Stories, 1983 Jul 8; 83-3012; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Henry Burton Sharman in Canadian History, Developing "Jesus As Teacher," Early seminars, Oxford group, 1983 Jul 8; 83-3013; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Klamath, Vancouver & Asilomar Seminars - Beginnings at Ben Lomond, 1983 Jul 8; 83-3015; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Topics?, 1983 Jul 8; 83-3017; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Las Alas Lodge, Walks & Scenery (with Ickegami camera), 1983 Jul 8; 83-3018; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - on path stories; Sunrise Lodge - stories (2 of 10), 1983 Jul 8; 831031A-2; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - First Meeting with Sharman, early years at Stanford (3 of 10), 1983 Jul 8; 831031A-3; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Crowd shots, first seminar at Minnesing (4 of 10), 831031A-4; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Sharman early years, Mrs. Sharman (5 of 10), 831031A-5; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Mrs. Sharman, Sharman's company, meticulous scholar/history Yen Jing. Teeth/leg stories (6 of 10), 831031A-6; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Sharman's Thesis, Chicago papers, Group Shots, Origins of JAT, Fritz Kunkel (7 of 10), 831031A-7; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - Oxford Group (8 of 10), 831031A-8; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - Harry Rathbun Teaching - [illegible] Gerald Heard (9 of 10), 831031A-9; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 3)
  - E. Rathbun 1st Mg. AMR, 1974 Aug 29; 4.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Study of Records - Lecture 2 (Bishop Aud.), 1977 Feb 12; 4.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Emila Ratbhun to AMR Group, Mt. View Academy, 1974 Oct 2; 4.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Emilia AMR Interview (Jesus), 4.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Side 1: Self-Assessment Course - Introduction to AMR, Creative Initiative Foundation; Side 2: Specifics of Course, 1977; 4.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Emilia (to men) "Anima", 1973 May 21; 4.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - T.S. 33 Anima-Animus, 4.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - TS-30 "C" Branch All day E & H Rathbun, 1973 Oct 27; 4.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun to C/C & C/T, 1974 Mar 14; 4.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - D seminar E. Rathbun "Transforming Basic Nature", 1973 Sep 8; 4.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Harry Rathbun Part A, 1975 Jul 3; 4.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Harry Rathbun Part B, 4.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Harry Rathbun Part C, 4.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - AMR Dream Talk (tape 1), 1977 Apr 1; 4.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - AMR Dream Talk (tape 2), 1977 Apr 1; 4.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - AMR Dreams (tape 1), 1977 Apr 1; 4.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - AMR Dreams (tape 2), 1977 Apr 1; 4.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion, Series IV: Lecture 15, 1977 Apr 1; 4.18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Rathbun and friends, Palo Alto (10/5); Mr. Rathbun (10/6), 1982 Oct 5-6; 4.19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Rathbun and friends, Palo Alto, 1982 Oct 5; 4.20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Mr. Rathbun (10/6); Mr. & Mrs. Rathbun, Palo Alto (10/7), 1982 Oct 6-7; 4.21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Rathbun, Palo Alto (2nd tape), 1982 Jul; 4.22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Mrs. Rathbun, Palo Alto, 1982 Oct 9; 4.23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Harry - History, 1985 Jan 29; 4.24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Study of Records - Lecture 2, 1977 Feb 12; 4.25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Harry & Emilia Rathbun - Memoirs - 1st session, 1981 Oct 4; 4.26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Harry Rathbun on JAT, 4.27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of John #2, 1977 Apr 14; 4.28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of John #3, 1977 Apr 28; 4.29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of John #4, 1977 May 12; 4.30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of John #1, 1977 Apr 7; 4.31; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of John #5, 1977 May 19; 4.32; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical study of records, lecture 2 (Bishop Aud.) (tape 1), 1977 Feb 12; 4.33; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical study of records, lecture 2 (Bishop Aud.) (tape 2), 1977 Feb 12; 4.34; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Marriage AMR Emilia Ratbun, 1974 Dec 9; 4.35; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Review of the Records, lecture 1 (tape 1), 1977 Feb 5; 4.36; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Review of the Records, lecture 1 (tape 2), 1977 Feb 5; 4.37; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Review of the Records, lecture III, 1977 Feb 19; 4.38; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Review of the Records, lecture IV, 1977 Feb 26; 4.39; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Review of the Records, lecture 5, 1977 Mar 5; 4.40; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Review of the Records, lecture 6, 1977 Mar 12; 4.41; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Review of the Records, lecture 7, 1977 Mar 26; 4.42; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Records Weekend, 1978 Oct 14; 4.43; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical Review of the Records, plus men's testimonials, lecture 8, 1977 Apr 16; 4.44; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun, et. al - mtg 9, 1977 Apr 23; 4.45; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - mtg 10, 1977 Apr 30; 4.46; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Record Weekend, 1978 Oct 14; 4.47; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical review of the records, 1977 May 14; 4.48; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Harry Rathbun - Mtg. 11, 1977 May 7; 4.49; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical review of the records (tape 1), 1977 Jun 4; 4.50; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - H. Rathbun - Critical review of the records (tape 2), 1977 Jun 4; 4.51; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Beginning Teaching - Jesus as Teacher, 4.52; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of Thomas, 2nd mtg., 1976 Mar 22; 4.53; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, the teacher, 4.54; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - (1+) 2, 4.55; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 3, 4.56; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 4, 4.57; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 5, 4.58; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 6, 4.59; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 7, 4.60; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 8, 4.61; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - 9, 4.62; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of John #2 Emilia, 1977 Apr 14; 4.63; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of John #3 Emilia, 1977 Apr 28; 4.64; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus #1, I, 1975 Oct 20; 4.65; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus #1, II, 1975 Oct 20; 4.66; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus #4, I, 1975 Nov 10; 4.67; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus #4, II, 1975 Nov 10; 4.68; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus #6, I, 1975 Nov 24; 4.69; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus The Teacher - Teaching on Prayer, 4.70; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus The Teacher - Prayer (continued), 4.71; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus The Teacher - The Final Days, 4.72; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Emilia Rathbun "Resistance", 1996 Feb 29; 4.73; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Archetypes, 4.74; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths, Series 1: Lecture 2: Pre-History Myths, 4.75; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - A Conversation about the early days with Emilia and Frances Horn, 1991 Dec 7; 4.76; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Afghan Team Report, 2002 Jun 12; 4.77; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Evolutionary Politics, Representative Dennis Kucinich - Ohio, 2002 Sep 28; 4.77; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - On Bridging Sorrow: September 11 Families Journey to Afghanistan, Kelly Campbell, 2002 May 22; 4.78; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Open House and Solar Celebration-222 High Street Palo Alto, CA, 2002 Sep 28; 4.79; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Emilia Rathbun and Stephen Crothers-Theosphere and the Implicate Order, 1996 Mar 7; 4.80; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Baptism and Wilderness, 4.81; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Entry into Jerusalem, 4.82; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Certain Parables, 4.83; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Sermon on the Mount, 4.84; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Sermon on the Mount & Kingdom of God, 4.85; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Beginning Teaching, 4.86; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The Historical Jesus: Overview, 4.87; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Introduction), 4.88; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Pre-History Myths), 4.89; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Jeremiah & Ezekiel), 4.90; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Series IV: Lecture 16: Feminine Principle), 4.91; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Series III: Lecture 12: Amos/Hosea/Isaiah), 4.92; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (The Feminine Principle), 4.93; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Series II: Lecture 6: Moses), 4.94; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Series I: Lecture 4: Isaac & Jacob), 4.95; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Pre-History Myths), 4.96; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Series IV: Lecture 13: Jeremiah/Ezekiel), 4.97; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Series IV: Lecture 13: Jeremiah/Ezekiel), 4.98; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Series II: Lecture 7: Joshua & Gideon), 4.99; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Amos, Hosea, Isaiah), 4.100; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Series II: Lecture 5: Joseph), 4.101; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Abraham), 4.102; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from Old Myths (Series I: Lecture 1: Introduction), 4.103; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Beginning Teaching Lecture II, 4.104; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Specific Teachings, 4.105; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Prayer, 4.106; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Certain Parables, 4.107; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Baptism & Wilderness, 4.108; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: The Final Days, 4.109; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Sermon on the Mount & Kingdom of God, 4.110; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Specific Teachings, 4.111; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths (Series I: Lecture 4: Isaac & Jacob), 4.112; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths (Series II: Lecture 6: Moses), 4.113; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of Thomas - 1st Meeting (Tape 1), 1976 Mar 8; 4.114; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of Thomas - 1st Meeting (Tape 2), 1976 Mar 8; 4.115; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of Thomas - 2nd Meeting (Tape 1), 1976 Mar 22; 4.116; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Book of Johns #4 Emilia, 1977 May 12; 4.117; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Modern Man in Search of a Soul, H. Rathbun, Intro Gary Williams, 1977 May 4; 4.118; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus #2, 1975 Oct 27; 4.119; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Jesus #6, 1975 Nov 24; 4.120; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Living meditation and prayer, 4.121; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Study of God, 4.122; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - I-Thou, 4.123; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Emilia Rathbun on "A Power Greater", 1996 Feb 24; 4.124; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Myths for Moderns - Lecture 1, 4.125; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The Teaching of Jesus: A Talk by Emily Rathbun, 1994 Jun 22; 4.126; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - Early Christian Church: Paul, 4.127; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - God, Self, Love and Others, 4.128; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 4)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths, Series II: Lecture 8: Saul & David, 5.1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Jesus, The Teacher: Sermon on the Mount, Lecture III, 5.2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Early Christian Church: Paul, 5.3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Myths for Moderns: Lecture 6, 5.4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Moses, 5.5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Joseph, 5.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Saul & David, 5.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Job, 5.8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Amos, Hoseah, & Isaiah, 5.9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Series II: Lecture 6: Moses, 5.10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Joseph, 5.11; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Elijah/Elisha, 5.12; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: The Feminine Principle, 5.13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Pre-History Myths, 5.14; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Isaac & Job, 5.15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Moses, 5.16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Jonah, 5.17; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Abraham, 5.18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Joshua & Gideon, 5.19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Daniel, 5.20; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Abraham, 5.21; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Summary, 5.22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Saul & David, 5.23; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Amos/Hosea/Isaiah, 5.24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Solomon, 5.25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Jeremiah & Ezekiel, 5.26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Jonah, 5.27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Solomon, 5.28; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Saul and David, 5.29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Elijah & Elisha, 5.30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Abraham, 5.31; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Summary, 5.32; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Job, 5.33; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - The New Religion: Contemporary Abstracts from the Old Myths: Isaac & Jacob, 5.34; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Myths for Moderns: Lecture 5, 5.35; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Myths for Moderns: Lecture 6, 5.36; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Myths for Moderns: Lecture 3, 5.37; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Myths for Moderns: Lecture 2, 5.38; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Myths for Moderns: Lecture 4, 5.39; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Myths for Moderns: Lecture 3, 5.40; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)
  - Myths for Moderns: Lecture 1, 5.41; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 5)